所以我们接下来要说的是标签，对吗 ?
So the next thing that we're gonna
be talking about is tags, right?
你可以在网页上看到我们要在 Docker中使用的标记。
So you can see here on the webpage
we're gonna go into Tags, under Docker.
所以我们有点在这个话题上跳舞。
And so we've kind of been dancing
around the topic a little bit.
但我想深入了解标记的深度，以及使用这些标记的原因，因此
But I wanna kinda get into depth with what
tags are, why you use them, so on and so
第四个
forth.
所以如果我在那儿做船坞就可以看到它
So you can see right there if I do
docker run -it node right there and
除了别的什么别的什么外围赛
I leave off anything else,
any sort of qualifier for that.
这意味着你要穿上最新的标签对吧
It implies that you're gonna
put on the latest tag, right?
最新的是少数标记之一。
And latest is one of the few tags.
就像一个特别的标签，对吧 ?
It's actually like a special tag, right?
它意味着您发布的最后一个。
It implies the last one that you publish.
这是你在做什么的最新版本吧
That is the latest version of
whatever you're doing, right?
所以你在捣乱的时候就没事了
So this is fine when
you're messing around,
就像我们现在所做的一样
kinda like what we're doing right now.
只要说很酷就好了给我最新的
It's fine to just say,
cool, give me the latest,
不管最新版本是什么
give me whatever the newest version is.
但每当你的环境或任何时候
But whenever you're making your
environments or whenever you're
这样做你想把它绑在特定的版本上
doing anything like that, you wanna
have it tied to a specific version.
因为我相信我们都有问题的附件
Because I'm sure we've all had issues
with appendices before where they've
半创造的东西坏了对吧
half-created and stuff broke, right?
我们想避免这种情况
We wanna avoid that.
这就是为什么在这个过程中我非常谨慎地
That's why in this particular course
I've been very careful to give
您要下载的特定标记。
you specific tags to download.
现在，你也许会问，是否有任何韵律或有标签的原因 ?
Now, you might ask, is there any sorta
rhyme or reason of how tags are made?
答案是，不是真的。
And the answer is, not really.
这不像 npm ，他们期待语义上的版本控制或者任何类似的东西。
It's not like npm, where they're expecting
semantic versioning or anything like that.
Docker 标记要松得多，对吗 ?
Docker tags are much more loose, right?
无论作者决定如何将标签命名。
It's whatever the author
decides to name the tags.
这里的一个例子是节点:这里是 8 个，对吧 ?
So an example of that would
be node:8 right here, right?
假设我有个根据节点 8的应用
Let's say I had something that I had
an app that dependent on node 8,
我可以说节点:8。
I can say node:8.
这会给我 8 个最新发行版的
And this will give me whatever
the latest release of 8 is,
我觉得舒服多了而不是什么最新的事
which I feel much more comfortable with,
rather than the latest of whatever.
现在，不要这样做，因为不推荐使用节点 8 ，对吗 ?
Now, don't do this because
Node 8 is deprecated, right?
已经不在服役了对吧
It's no longer in service, right?
所以它没有得到安全修复或者类似的东西。
So it's not getting security fixes or
anything like that.
但它还在外面
But it's still out there.
如果你需要的话你可以做到的好吗
If you needed it, you could do that, okay?
因此，我们继续关注 Docker Hub 页面。
So let's go ahead and take a look
at the Docker Hub page for that.
这是节点容器的 Docker Hub 页面，对吗 ?
This is the Docker Hub page for
the Node container, right?
任何一个集装箱里的每个人都要
And everyone at any one of these
containers are all gonna have
某种类型的 Docker Hub 页面。
some sort of Docker Hub page.
你可以在这里看到，这些标签都存在，对吧 ?
So you can see here, these all of
the labels that exist for this, right?
有很多节点容器。
There are a lot of node containers.
那为什么呢
Now, why is that?
你可以看到，你可以要求很多非常具体的事情，对吗 ?
You can see here you can request
a lot of very specific things, right?
所以如果我来这里我们就要求
So if I come down here,
we've been asking for
12 张是这张的
12 stretch which is this one right there.
但你可以看到有很多不同的事物
But you can see there is a lot of
different things that all refer to
一样的对吧
the same thing, right?
我们可以把它称为 " 双 - 拉伸" 。
We could've referred to
this as erbium-stretch.
因为，从技术上来说，节点 12 是节点的铒释放。
Because, technically,
Node 12 is the erbium release of node.
不是你需要知道的
Not that you ever needed to know that.
我完全忘记了，直到我现在才看了它。
And I totally forgot that until
I just read it right now.
所以它有一个名字，而不仅仅是没有人这么叫它。
So it does have a name,
not just no one ever calls it that.
但你可以把它称为 LTS 拉伸的 LTS
But you could refer it to as
LTS stretch which LTS is like,
节点 12 是节点的最新 LTS， right。
Node 12 is the latest LTS,
right, for a Node.
或者你可以只说点 " 点 " ，对吧 ?
Or you could just actually
just said node:lts, right?
这指的是拉伸 Debian 的 LTS 和节点的 LTS 。
Which have been referred to the LTS of
stretch Debian and the LTS of node.
我还是不建议这样做虽然我不觉得这是个好主意
I'm still not gonna recommend that though
I don't think that's a good idea because
当 LTS 向前滚动时，向右，当我们移动到节点 14 时，以及 Debian 10。
as that LTS rolls forward, right,
when we move on to Node 14, and Debian 10.
或者下一个 Debian 会成为下一个 LTS 的版本，对吧 ?
Or whatever the next version of Debian
that's gonna be the next LTS, right?
那个 LTS 的标签会和它一起滚动的对吧
That LTS tag is going to
roll along with it, right?
如果你建造一个应用，就像坐在架子上 5 年，
And if you build an app and then it's like
sitting on the shelf for five years, and
然后你就回来说 LTS 会很不一样对吧
then you come back to it that LTS
is gonna be very different, right?
这些都是你想要思考的东西
So these are the kinda things you
wanna be thinking through is like,
我怎么能及时把握这一刻才能让这一刻不再发生
how can I capture this moment in time so
this doesn't break in the future?
这就是你想用容器做的事
That's what you wanna do with containers.
但这里还有其他事对吧
But there's other things here, right?
有弹性的，对吧 ?
There's stretch-slim, right?
到目前为止，我们一直在下载完整的 Debian ，对吧 ?
So so far, we've been downloading
the full Debian, right?
但我们可以说 12 条细长的
But we could say 12-stretch-slim, and
根据他们的定义，没有特别的定义，但这将会
by their definition that there's no
special definition of slim but this will
给我们一个更苗条的版本或者就像一个小版本的 Debian，对吧 ?
give us a more slender version or
like a smaller version of Debian, right?
通常，由于几个原因，您想拥有最小的容器。
In general you wanna have the smallest
container possible for several reasons.
有一个完整的章节让我们稍后再讨论
And there's a whole section on that so
we'll get to that later but
甚至超出了伸展的范围对吧
there's even beyond stretch, right?
还有杰西和巴斯特这些都是 Debian 的其他版本吧
There's Jesse and Buster and these are
other versions of Debian as well, right?
你也可以在这里看到我们可以在高山上运行，对吧 ?
You can also see here that
we can run in Alpine, right?
所以我可以说，给我点冒号，阿尔卑斯的破折号，什么，对吧 ?
So I can say, give me node colon,
Alpine dash, whatever, right?
所有这些版本都存在。
And all those versions exists as well.
里面还有什么 ?
What else is in there?
这里甚至还有 chakracore
There's even chakracore down here.
哪个 chakracore 实际上是 JavaScript 引擎
Which chakracore is actually
the JavaScript engine that's baked into
Microsoft Edge ，旧版本，对吧 ?
Microsoft Edge, the old version, right?
他们拿走了这个，把它放进了节点。
And they took that and
they put that into Node.
所以不要跑 V8
So instead of running V8,
这就是 Chrome 的存在你可以使用 chakracore
which is what's in Chrome,
you can actually use chakracore.
我不建议即使是在微软工作的人
Now, I don't recommend that,
even as someone who works in Microsoft,
因为我们都不支持 Chakra 了
because we don't even
support Chakra anymore.
我们也要去铬化
We're moving to Chromium as well.
所以就可以说有很多不同的版本。
So suffice to say there's
a lot of different versions.
所以它会让你和
And so it behooves you and
准确的了解你想要什么的版本是吧
figure out exactly which versions
of what that you want, right?
想找出正确的标签
To figure out the right tags.
我觉得我给你的那个很不错
I think the one that I gave
you is a pretty good one.
如果你放弃了对吧
If you give it stretch, right?
如果后面有更多的安全补丁，你会想要这些，对吧 ?
If there's more security patches that
come out later you want those, right?
您希望自动合并到容器中。
You want those to automatically be
incorporated into your containers.
这就是为什么它很依赖拉伸的原因，对吧 ?
That's why it's good dependent to stretch,
right?
然后我认为对 12 的依赖程度非常强，因为作为次要的补丁版本
And then I think it's good dependence to
12 because it as minor patch versions come
你也会想要这些的
out, you'll probably want those as well.
但如果你想跟 13 号节点乱搞的话你完全可以做到的对吧
But if you wanna mess around with node 13,
you can totally do that, right?
所以你可以看到，最晚的是，对吧 ?
So you can see there,
that's what latest is, right?
那是 13.3.0- 拉伸
It's 13.3.0-stretch.
如果不是显而易见的，每条线，
In case it wasn't obvious,
each one these lines,
这些都是同一个容器吧
these are all the same container, right?
它们都是同一个容器的各种标签。
They're all various tags for
the same container.
>> 如何确定要执行哪个操作 ?
&gt;&gt; How do you decide
which one do you want?
我知道你提到这取决于你的需要
I know you mentioned that
depends on your needs.
但这是否是某种经验法则 ?
But is this some kinda rule of thumb?
我知道你刚才说伸缩是好的，但是
I know you just mentioned that
stretch is good version, but
每一个容器都有类似的缺省值
does every container have sort of like,
hey, here's kinda the default one.
当不确定的时候选择这个
When in doubt, pick this one.
>> 是。
&gt;&gt; Yes.
所以我认为有好的经验法则
So I think there are good
rules of thumb for
像这样像一个 " 节点容器 " 一样适用于 Ruby 或类似的东西。
something like this, like a Node container
and apply to Ruby or something like that.
我去找最新的 LTS 给我最新的 LTS 和最新的 LTS
I would go find the latest LTS for the
Linux that I'm on and the latest LTS for
要么要么去要么去要么就把它绑起来好吗
the Node or go or whatever I'm on and
then tie it to that, right?
这就是为什么这两个最新的 LTS 的 12 个伸缩库都是针对这两个的原因。
So that's why the 12 stretch cuz of
the two latest LTS is for both of those.
现在如果我只是在捣乱
Now, if I'm just messing
around with something,
我要做最新和最伟大的技术对吧
I'll just do latest cuz I wanna play
the latest and greatest tech, right?
但你现在不想发货 13 号节点对吧
But you don't wanna ship
Node 13 right now, right?
这被认为是当前版本的节点
That's considered
the current version of Node,
这意味着他们在做实验之类的事
which means that they're experimenting and
things like that.
不能保证它不会破裂什么的
There's no promises that it's not
gonna break or anything like that.
因此， 12 对于您的生产工作负载是好的。
So that's why it's good to be on 12 for
your production workloads.
>> So [COUGH] ，例如， 12.13.2 出来时，
&gt;&gt; So [COUGH] when, for
example, 12.13.2 comes out,
是这个名单上的另一个条目
is that another entry in this list or
是否会覆盖或覆盖此 kinda 列表?
do patches get overwritten or
overwrite this kinda list?
星星 >> 右边。
Star.
&gt;&gt; Right.
>> 如果每次都是这样我们就会有更多的
&gt;&gt; Cuz it seems like there'd be even
more than this if it was every single
补丁版本。
patch version ever.
> > 是这样，您可以将其定义为特定补丁发行版 ( 如果
&gt;&gt; Yeah so you can definately tie
it to a specific patch release if
你觉得那是 importnat
you felt that was importnat.
我不会建议这样做的。
I would not suggest that.
>> 右边。 我想我主要是问
&gt;&gt; Right.
I guess I was mostly asking,
如果你用 12.13.1的制作
cuz if you created it with 12.13.1,
你只是想让我们说 12 个吧我猜是我的问题
Do you just want us to say 12,
I guess is my question,
主版本，然后离开次和补丁?
the major version, and
then leave off the minor and patch?
> > 是的，如果我把它绑在 12.10，对，或者什么的，我们现在就在 12 . 13。
&gt;&gt; Yeah, so if I tied it to 12.10, right,
or whatever, we're on right now, 12.13.
所以如果我 12 点 13 的话，它会上升到 0.4，对吧 ?
So if I did 12.13,
it would bump up to 0.4, right?
但不会碰到 12.14，对吧 ?
But it would not bump up to 12.14, right?
那就有13 个了
It would keep it on 13.
所以这里有更多的版本甚至没有被列出。
So there are more versions
here that are not even listed.
> > 好的谢谢
&gt;&gt; Okay, thank you.
> > 是。
&gt;&gt; Yep.
你知道这事很重要对吧
It's important stuff for
you to know, right?
知道如何把它绑在正确的版本上是很重要的
It's important stuff to know how to
tie it to the correct versions of what
你在等我
you're expecting.
每个 Docker 页面都会为您提供这些信息。
And every Docker Page is
gonna have these for you.
所以有些人不同意我的意见就像我 12 岁一样
So there are people that would disagree
with me, like I do 12 stretch,
有人会说要做 12.13，对，破折号，
there are people that would say
just do 12.13, right, dash stretch,
他们会把它保留在相同的小版本上
cuz they would keep it to
the same minor version.
我想大家都同意，让补片卷是个好主意
I think everyone would universally agree,
it's a good idea to let patches roll
不管怎么说因为这意味着你会得到安全补丁
forward no matter what, because that
means you'll get the security patches.
我将断言，我从未有过一个次版本的 Node 破坏我正在做的事情。
I would assert that I've never had a minor
version of Node break what I'm doing.
它们对节点的主要版本控制很有好处，
They're pretty good about
major versioning with Node,
所以我对他们有很大的信任
so I have a lot of trust in them.
我和他们一起在微软工作，他们非常谨慎。
And I work with them at Microsoft and
they're very careful about it.
但这取决于你对容器的作者的信任程度，对吧 ?
But it depends on how much you trust
the authors of the container, right?
如果您是基于某个 Joe's Crab Shack 和 Node Container 的人 ?
If you're based on someone
Joe's Crab Shack and Node container right?
那也许你就不相信他们了对吧
Then maybe you trust them a bit less,
right?
就看
It just depends